sergiorossi.com 2014-04-13

# Sergio Rossi Online Store - Legal Area

Welcome to our website www.sergiorossi.com (the “ **Site** ”). Please read our Privacy Policy carefully. 

This Privacy Policy applies when you visit or surf the Site without purchasing any product, when you register on the Site and when you use our services for purchasing products. By using this Site, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not want to accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site. 

Since personal data (“ **Personal Data** ”) of users and customers (collectively " **Users** ") of this Site may be processed in the European Union, notably in Italy, any processing of Personal Data will be conducted in compliance with applicable European laws. 

Your personal data are collected and processed by Sergio Rossi S.p.A. and the companies of the Kering Group (the "Kering Group") as well as by their service providers located within and outside of the European Union (collectively " **us** ", " **we** ", " **our** "). Sergio Rossi S.p.A. has its registered offices in Via Stradone 600/602 47030 SAN MAURO PASCOLI (FC), Italia and may be contacted at privacy@store.sergiorossi.com for any issue relating to this privacy policy. 

Your Personal Data will be processed to provide the services you subscribed to or reserved for registered users, to facilitate your navigation of and shopping from the website and to keep you informed of Kering Group news and offers. 

Sergio Rossi S.p.A. and the companies of Kering Group are jointly controllers of Personal Data collected and processed for purpose of rendering the e-commerce services and the sale of products (herein the " **Commercial Purposes** ") through the Site, together with YOOX S.p.A. with registered offices in Via Nannetti 1, 40069 Zola Predosa (BO), Italy, Bologna Business Register, Tax and VAT number 02050461207, share capital Euro 583,082.76 fully paid up. 

The management of the sale of the products and the transactions performed on www.sergiorossi.com, within the United States of America are operated, under license, by YOOX S.p.A.’ s subsidiary YOOX Corporation, a Delaware corporation having an address at 148 Lafayette Street, 10th Floor, New York, New York 10013 ("YOOX USA", YOOX S.p.A. and YOOX USA also jointly referred to as YOOX). 

YOOX USA is the controller of personal data of users and customers of the Site within the United States of America, which is collected for conducting, concluding and performing transactions for purchasing products on the aforementioned site. As required by the Italian Data Protection Code, YOOX USA has appointed YOOX S.p.A. as its data protection representative in Italy. As our data protection representative in Italy, YOOX S.p.A. ensures that personal data are processed in Italy in a correct and lawful manner and in accordance with good practice. Since personal data of users and customers collected for conducting, concluding and performing purchase transactions through the Site in the United States of America may be processed in Italy, any such processing of personal data will be conducted in compliance with applicable US law as well as the Italian Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 dated June 30, 2003). 

Sergio Rossi S.p.A. and the companies of Kering Group are the sole data controllers of the Personal Data processed for marketing purposes, notably to send to Users, also through newsletter, information and updates on its products, offers, exclusive sales, promotional campaigns and on events and similar initiatives organized by Sergio Rossi S.p.A. or the companies of Kering Group (herein the " **Marketing Purposes** "). 

**1\. Our Policy**

Everyone has the right to protection of his/her Personal Data. We and YOOX respect Users' right to be informed regarding the collection of and other operations involving their Personal Data. In using data that may directly or indirectly identify you personally, we will apply a principle of strict necessity. For this reason, we and YOOX have designed the Site in such a way that the use of your Personal Data will be kept to a minimum and will not exceed the purposes for which your Personal Data was collected and/or processed; we and YOOX do not process your Personal Data when we can provide you with services through the use of anonymous or traffic data (such as marketing research made for improving our services, browsing data processed to provide you with customized contents or offers adapted to your preferred language, your location, etc) or by other means which allow us and YOOX to identify you, apart from when it is strictly necessary or upon request by competent public authorities or the police (for example, in case of traffic data or your IP address). 

This Privacy Policy provides you with all information needed to understand how we and YOOX collect data which may identify the Site’s Users. For further information on our Privacy Policy, please contact us or YOOX at privacy@store.sergiorossi.com, or at YOOX or Sergio Rossi S.p.A. at their respective registered offices indicated above. 

**2\. Who collects and processes Your Personal Data, how and for which purposes?**

YOOX, Sergio Rossi S.p.A. and the companies of Kering Group may be jointly or respectively the controllers of your Personal Data as they determine the Commercial Purposes and means of processing Personal Data. For the Commercial Purposes only, YOOX and Sergio Rossi have appointed certain entities that will also process Personal Data relating to the Site’s Users (herein the " **Processors** "). 

The above mentioned service providers and Processors have been chosen because of their experience in processing Personal Data and they provide sufficient guarantees regarding compliance with data protection laws (including the technical security measures governing the processing to be carried out). In processing the Personal Data for Commercial Purposes, the Processors shall act only under the instructions from Yoox or from Sergio Rossi S.p.A.. We regularly check that our Processors comply with our instructions and that they continue to provide sufficient guarantees regarding their full compliance with the provisions on Personal Data processing. 

Some of the Processors of your Personal Data appointed by YOOX for Commercial Purposes directly are: 

United Parcel Service, for purposes related to shipping, delivering and returning products purchased on www.sergiorossi.com; 

BT Italia S.p.A., for purposes related to the housing of YOOX servers; 

Prestige International UK ltd, for purposes connected to providing call centre and Customer Care services to the Site’s Users. 

For the Commercial Purposes, we and YOOX collect your Personal Data (such as personal details, e-mail address, address, Credit Card numbers, bank code, tax code and telephone number, etc.) on your order form only for the purpose of selling the products ordered by you. Your Personal Data is mostly processed by electronic means and, in some circumstances, by paper-based means, such as when the processing of your Personal Data is required for preventing fraud on the Site. Your Personal Data shall be stored in a way which allows us and YOOX to identify you for the period necessary for the purposes which the data was collected for and subsequently processed and, in any case, in accordance with applicable laws. Please report any modification of your Personal Data to privacy@store.sergiorossi.com or through you personal account on the Site in order to ensure that your Personal Data is always accurate and up-to-date, relevant and complete. Your Personal Data shall not be disclosed to third parties other than us and YOOX for purposes which are not permitted by law or without your consent. 

Aside from the Processors appointed for Personal Data processing, your Personal Data will be made available also to third parties, autonomous controllers, for purposes related to supplying services requested by Users (for example, for purchase transactions) or for purposes of third parties. For more information on the matter, see section 4 (To Whom Your Personal Data Will Be Disclosed). Please contact our Customer Care or send us an e-mail at privacy@store.sergiorossi.com if you would like to receive a full list of our data Processors involved in processing your Personal Data. 

For the Marketing Purposes, we may process your Personal Data as well as browsing data (" **Traffic data** ") resulting from the use of the Site and of our services by any User, in order to provide Users with customized contents and offers on our services or to deliver any newsletter they subscribed to, subject to their discretionary right to withdraw their subscription to such newsletter or to oppose or object to the receiving of any advertising or marketing content which we think is of interest to a specific User. For Marketing Purposes, Personal Data and Traffic data is mostly processed by electronic means and shall be stored for us in any case, in accordance with applicable laws and available to our Processors. 

Moreover, your Personal Data may be disclosed to the police or to judicial authorities, according to applicable laws and upon a formal request by such entities, for example in the event we need to prevent fraud on the Site (anti-fraud services). 

Data processors will also have access to your Personal Data as stated in section 2 for the specific purposes stated therein. In all the above circumstances, your consent for data processing is not required as Personal Data Processing would be necessary for the performance of Commercial Purposes. 

The reasons for collecting Personal Data will be expressly listed in the information of privacy statement that we will present from time to time on the page asking the User to provide his or her Personal Data, be it for Commercial Purposes or for Marketing Purposes. We and YOOX may have access to third parties' Personal Data which was directly disclosed by its Users, for example when a User bought a product to be sent to a friend, when the User paying for the product is different from the recipient of the product, or when a User wishes to recommend to a friend a service of the Site or the sale of a particular product. In all of the above cases, please make sure you receive the consent of such individuals before disclosing their Personal Data to us and make sure you inform them about this Privacy Policy; you will be the only person liable in connection with the disclosure of information and data regarding such third parties if they have not provided you with their prior explicit consent for it and for any improper and unlawful use of that information. In any event, we and YOOX shall fulfill any obligation to inform third parties required by law and, when necessary, shall request their explicit consent upon registering in their archives the Personal Data of the User indicated. 

**3\. What Happens if You Do Not Disclose Your Personal Data to us?**

Granting your Personal Data to us and YOOX (in particular, your personal details, your e-mail address, your address, your Credit/Debit Card numbers and bank code and your telephone number) is necessary for processing your order for the purchase of products on the Site, supplying other services provided on the web site upon your request, or when your Personal Data is needed to fulfill obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us and YOOX with some of your Personal Data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us or YOOX from processing your order for the purchase of products sold on the Site or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failing to provide Personal Data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not processing your order for the purchase of products sold on the Site or not providing the Site’s services. 

Disclosure of further Personal Data to us and YOOX other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to be properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Site and of its services or on the purchase of products on the Site. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your Personal Data to us and YOOX is compulsory or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is compulsory or data needed for the purchase of products on the Site. 

**4\. To Whom Your Personal Data Will Be Disclosed?**

Personal Data will be disclosed to third party companies that provide, on behalf of Sergio Rossi S.p.A., specific services as data Processors or to other recipients of Personal Data collected by us or YOOX that process your Personal Data only for the Commercial Purposes (for example, Banca Sella S.p.A.) and, in any case, according to applicable laws and regulations. 

Your Personal Data is also intended to the companies belonging to Kering’s Group, with registered offices in EU countries or non EU countries, for their own Marketing Purposes.

Please send an e-mail at privacy@store.sergiorossi.com if you would like to receive a full updated list of Kering’s Group companies. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, Personal Data will not be disclosed to any other third parties or disseminated or transferred without informing our Users of such disclosure/dissemination/transfer, and, in any case, in accordance with the applicable laws. 

**5\. Security Measures**

We have adopted security measures to protect Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, and against all other reasons for data processing that do not comply with our Privacy Policy. For the best possible protection of your Personal Data outside the limits of our or YOOX's control and management of the same, it is advisable that your computer be provided with software devices that protect network data transmission/receipt (such as updated antivirus systems) and that your Internet service provider take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering). 

**6\. Cookies**

The Site uses automatic systems of traffic data collection, such as cookies. A cookie is a file stored on the hard disk of the terminal of an Internet user; it does not contain intelligible information but it allows linking between a terminal and other information about User's experience on the Site and his/her preferences expressed while choosing services and purchasing products offered by the Site) provided by the Users. For Cookies disseminated by our servers, no one else may gain access to the information contained therein. These information and data are gathered directly and automatically by the Site. The information collected by cookies will be processed in order to optimize the services of the Site. We and YOOX have provided cookies in connection to functions such as selecting the country, the language, the location, browsing the catalogue, purchasing products online and in general in connection with the provision of services reserved to registered customers. Each Internet browser allows the blocking or the deletion of cookies. Your Internet browser contains instructions on these procedures. Please access the information on your Internet browser if you wish to delete cookies. 

The acceptance of automatic data collection procedures and the use of cookies are necessary for using the Site and its services, including the purchase of products. If you have started the procedure of blocking or deleting cookies, us or YOOX cannot ensure that all web pages of the Site will be displayed or that certain services will be supplied such as, for example, storage or display on the web pages of products you chose when you were finalizing the online purchase processes. 

**7\. Compulsory processing**

We wish to inform you that us or YOOX may process your Personal Data also without your consent in certain circumstances provided by laws. 

**8\. Your Right to Access Personal Data and Further Rights**

You are entitled to obtain, at any time, confirmation from us or YOOX as to whether or not data relating to you is being processed, whether the data is not yet registered, and the communication in intelligible form of the data undergoing processing. You are entitled to obtain, at any time, confirmation from us or YOOX as to whether or not data relating to you is being processed, whether the data is not yet registered, and the communication in intelligible form of the data undergoing processing. Moreover, you are entitled to receive from us or YOOX information on the source of your Personal Data; the purposes and way of processing your Personal Data; the logic involved in any electronic data processing; details of the data controller and of the data processors; the names of the entities and categories of entities to whom your Personal Data may be disclosed or who may access your Personal Data, for example, as a data controller or a party so appointed. You can easily find part of the above information in our Privacy Policy. For further information, send an e-mail to privacy@store.sergiorossi.com. 

You are entitled to obtain at any time from us or YOOX: 

a. the updating, adjustment or, when you have an interest in such, the integration of your personal data; 

b. the deletion, the transformation into an anonymous form or blocking of your personal data (unlawfully processed), including data which does not need to be stored for the purposes for which it was collected and subsequently processed; 

c. the confirmation that the operations under letters a) and b) have been reported (together with the contents of the same) to whom the data was disclosed or disseminated, except when it becomes impossible or if the means used are clearly disproportionate to the right's protection. 

You are entitled to object, in whole or in part: 

a. for legitimate reasons, to the processing of your personal data, even if it is related to the purposes for which it was collected; 

b. to the processing of your personal data for advertising or direct marketing purposes or in order to carry out marketing research or commercial communications. 

You may freely exercise your rights at any time, provided that you do so in compliance with applicable laws, by sending your request to us or YOOX at the following e-mail address: privacy@store.sergiorossi.com or by writing to us at our respective address mentioned in introduction to this Privacy Policy. We or YOOX will reply to you as necessary. 

**9\. Opt-in/Opt out**

Each time your consent is required, Sergio Rossi S.p.A. will inform you in advance and will give you the option to either provide or refuse your consent for the use of your Personal Data, including your e-mail address, for the above purposes, by ticking the appropriate boxes. 

We wish to inform you that us or YOOX may process your Personal Data also without your consent in certain circumstances, such as when such processing is necessary for performing a legal obligation to which us or YOOX are subject or when such processing is necessary for performing obligations undertaken in contracts with the users. 

To the extent of applicable laws and subject to your rights, Your personal data may be processed by us for sending you advertising or offers for Marketing Purposes about products and services unless you object to it at any time, either when Your personal data has been collected or at any time, notably when receiving any offer from Us. 

In any case, we wish to inform you that YOOX and us guarantee that its users may exercise, at any time and without having to state their reasoning, their right not to receive future communications connected to particular services upon request. 

**10\. Links to Other Web Sites**

We or YOOX do not control or monitor such web sites or their web content. We or YOOX shall not be held liable for the web content of such sites and for the rules adopted by them in terms of your privacy and the processing of your Personal Data while you are visiting those web sites. Please, pay attention when you connect to these web sites through the links provided on our web site and read their terms and conditions of use and their privacy policy carefully. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third party web sites and we or YOOX are by no means liable for the privacy policy adopted by those web sites. The Site provides links to other web sites exclusively to help its Users in their searches and net-surfing activities and to allow links to other web sites on the Internet. When we or YOOX provide links to other web sites, we do not recommend the use of these web sites and do not provide any guarantees regarding their web content or the services and products supplied and sold by these web sites to Internet Users. 

**11\. Contacts**

If you wish to receive further information on how we or YOOX process your Personal Data, please send an e-mail to privacy@store.sergiorossi.com. 

**12\. Governing Law**

To the extent that we and YOOX are established in Italy, this Privacy Policy is governed by Italian law and, in particular, by the Italian Personal Data Protection Code which governs the processing of Personal Data - also held overseas - carried out by anyone who is domiciled or has registered offices in Italy. The Italian Personal Data Protection Code guarantees that processing of Personal Data will be carried out in compliance with fundamental rights and freedom of individuals, as well as of their dignity, with particular reference to confidentiality, identity and to the right to Personal Data protection. 

**13\. Amendments and Updating of this Privacy Policy**

We and YOOX may amend or simply update all or part of this Privacy Policy, including when amendments are made to legal provisions or regulations which govern data protection and protect your rights. The amendments and the updating of the Privacy Policy shall be binding as soon as they are published on the Site in this section. Therefore, you are requested to regularly access this section in order to check the publication of the most recent and updated Privacy Policy.
